Guide to the Gerald Stern Papers, 1920s-2012 SC.2007.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Gerald Stern Papers
1920-2012
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Stern, Gerald
SC.2007.04
60.25 Linear Feet (57 boxes)
Gerald Stern, the first Poet Laureate of New Jersey and Chancellor of the American Academy of American Poets, was born in Pittsburgh, Pa., on February 22, 1925 to Polish and Ukrainian immigrant parents. He received degrees from the University of Pittsburgh (BA in Political Science 1947) and Columbia University (MA in English 1949). He was the author of over fifteen books of poetry, two collections of essays, a one verse play, and in 2014 he published a book of his drawings. In addition, he received a number of nationally recognized awards, including the 1998 National Book Award for This Time: New and Selected Poems.The collection consists of manuscripts of Stern's poems and essays, including associated material, as well as correspondence, drawings, photographs, and audio and video recordings, making it a valuable resource in understanding Stern's creative process, influences in his life and his impact on national culture. Mr. Stern died on October 29, 2022 in Bronx, New York
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Acquired from Gerald Stern on November 27, 2007. Additional materials acquired in January 2014.
Arrangement
The collecton is organized into twelve series, as described below:
Series I. Poetry and Other Works
Series II. Articles, Essays, Lectures, Workshops and Other Projects
Series III. Drawings
Series IV. Correspondence
Series V. Publicity
Series VI. Readings
Series VII. General Activities
Series VIII. Poems, Essays, etc. for and about Gerald Stern
Series IX. Manuscripts by Others
Series X. Published Works
Series XI. Photographs
Series XII. Media Material
Biography
Gerald Daniel Stern was born February 22, 1925 in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. His parents, Harry and Ida Barach Stern, were Jewish immigrants from the Ukraine and Poland, respectively, who lived on Wylie Avenue in the city's Hill District, but later moved to an apartment on Beechwood Boulevard in the heavily Jewish neighborhood of Squirrel Hill. The second of two children, Stern was deeply affected by the death of his older sister, Sylvia, from cerebrospinal meningitis when he was eight years old. Stern attended Pittsburgh public schools, graduating from Taylor Allderdice High School in 1942. He was then admitted to the University of Pittsburgh, where he majored in English and was a member of the Men's Debating Association and Men's Glee Club. He received a Bachelor of Arts degree from Pitt in 1947 and a Master of Arts degree from Columbia University in 1949. He did post-graduate study at the Université de Paris (1949-1950) and at Columbia University (1950-1952), but never completed the coursework necessary for a Ph.D. On September 12, 1952, Stern married Patricia Miller, with whom he has two children, David and Rachel. Stern and his wife divorced in the late 1980s.
Stern served in the United States Army Air Corps in 1946 and 1947. From 1951 to 1953, he was an English teacher and later principal at Lake Grove School, Long Island, N.Y. In 1954, during a tour of Europe with his wife Pat, he taught at Victoria Drive Senior Secondary School in Glasgow, Scotland. Upon returning to the United States in 1956, Stern accepted the position of instructor in Temple University's English Department, where he taught until 1963. From 1963 to 1967, he served as an assistant professor in the English Department at Indiana University of Pennsylvania, and from 1968 to 1982 he was a professor at Somerset County (later known as Raritan Valley) Community College in Somerville, N.J. During this latter period, he also conducted poetry workshops at Lafayette College in Easton, Pa., (1975-1978) and Sarah Lawrence College in Bronxville, N.Y. (Spring 1977), as well as serving as a visiting professor at the University of Pittsburgh (Fall 1978) and Columbia University (1980). Stern also acted as literature consultant to both New Jersey's and Pennsylvania's Council of the Arts, as well as coordinator of the Pennsylvania Poetry in the Schools Program (1974-1978).
In 1982, Stern joined the faculty at the University of Iowa's Writers' Workshop, where he held the position of senior poet until 1995. He continued his visits to other universities, serving as Chairman of Creative Writing at the University of Alabama at Tuscaloosa (1984); Fanny Hurst Professor at Washington University in St. Louis, Mo. (1985); Visiting Professor at Bucknell University in Lewisburg, Pa. (1988); Holder of Bain Swiggert Chair at Princeton University (1989); Visiting Professor at New York University (1989); and Poet-in-Residence at Bucknell University (1994). In 2002, Stern co-founded the New England College's Master of Fine Arts (MFA) Program in Poetry with friend and former student Chard deNiord, and served as one of its inaugural faculty members. Most recently, Stern became a Distinguished Poet-in-Residence for the MFA Program in Poetry at Drew University, Madison, N.J., in January 2009.
Gerald Stern is the author of over fifteen books of poetry, two collections of personal essays, a one verse play, and a book of drawings. His first major published work was a long poem entitled "The Pineys," which first appeared in the Journal of the Rutgers University Library in 1969, when Stern was 44. Since then, he has given countless poetry readings and lectures throughout the United States and Europe and conducted several poetry workshops. He has been awarded numerous prestigious honors and prizes for his work. Among these are:
National Endowment of the Arts (NEA) Master Poet of Pennsylvania Grant, 1973-1975; NEA Creative Writing Grants, 1976, 1981, 1987; 1977 Lamont Poetry Selection Award for Lucky Life; 1978 Nominee, National Book Critics Circle Award for Lucky Life; 1979 Pennsylvania Creative Writing Grant; 1980 Pennsylvania Governor's Award for Excellence in the Arts; 1980 Guggenheim Foundation Fellowship; 1980 Bess Hokin Award for Poetry; 1981 Paris Review's Bernard F. Connor Award; 1982 Melville Caine Award from the Poetry Society of America for The Red Coal; 1984 Jerome J. Shestack Poetry Prize from the Academy of American Poets; 1992 Paterson Poetry Prize from Passaic County (N.J.) Community College for Bread Without Sugar; 1993 Fellow of the Academy of American Poets; 1996 Ruth Lilly Poetry Prize for Lifetime Achievement; 1998 National Book Award for Poetry for This Time: New and Selected Poems; 2000-2002 Poet Laureate of New Jersey; 2005 Wallace Stevens Award; 2005 National Jewish Book Award for Poetry; 2006 Chancellor of the Academy of American Poets; 2012 class of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences; 2012 recipient of the Rebekah Johnson Bobbitt National Prize for Poetry from the Library of Congress; 2014 winner of the Frost Medal.
Previous Citation
Gerald Stern Papers, 1920-2012, SC.2007.04, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
The Gerald Stern Papers consist of manuscripts of his poems, essays, drawings, correspondence, publications in which his works appeared, photographs, and audio and/or video recordings of many of his readings, lectures and interviews. It is a valuable resource in understanding Stern's creative process, influences in his life, and his impact on national culture. The collection covers Stern's life from his early years through his writing and teaching career.
New materials were added to the collection in 2015. These materials are identified at the end of each applicable series or subseries as "2015 Addition."
Drawings (Visual works); Personal papers; Photographs; Slides (Photographs); Negatives (Photographic); Notebooks; Lambertville (N.J.); Easton (Pa.); Pittsburgh (Pa.); College teachers -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Faculty; Poetry -- Competitions; Poetry -- Publishing; Poetry -- Study and teaching -- United States; Poets as teachers -- United States; Poets, American -- 20th century; New England Review; New Yorker (New York, N.Y.: 1925); American Poetry Review; Iowa City (Iowa); New York (N.Y.); Correspondence; Manuscripts (Documents); Typescripts; Audiotapes; Audiocassettes; Videocassettes; Clippings (Information artifacts); Cartoons (Humorous images); Caricatures; W.W. Norton & Company; Harper & Row, Publishers; Spring Church Book Company; Houghton, Mifflin and Company; Orlovitz, Gil; Pinsker, Sanford; Barnstone, Aliki; Hall, Mary Anne; Rosenberg, Liz; Buckley, Christopher; DeNiord, Chard; Van Brunt, Lloyd; Keys, Kerry Shawn; Schwartz, Lynne Sharon; Somerville, Jane; Moss, Howard; Hall, James; Davis, Christopher; Hillringhouse, Mark; Daniels, Guy; Irwin, Mark; Costanza, Jerry; Barber, Al; Robbins, Doren; Anderson, Maggie; Stricker, Meredith; Del Vecchio, Gloria C.; Murray, Joan; Levine, Philip; Hazley, Richard; Vogelsang, Arthur; Gilbert, Jack; McHugh, Heather; Roberts, Len; Digges, Deborah; Schulman, Grace; Lee, Li-Young; Hoagland, Tony; Mitchell, Susan; Sadoff, Ira; Barnstone, Willis; Berg, Stephen; Solataroff, Ted; Stern, Gerald; Stern, Ida Barach; Stern, Harry; Stern, David; Stern, Rachel; Stern, Patricia Miller; Macari, Anne Marie; Summers, Robert; Moyers, Bill D.; Galassi, Jonathan; Ochester, Ed; Smith, Carol Houck; New England College. MFA Program in Poetry; Iowa Writers' Workshop; Columbia University; University of Pittsburgh; University of Pittsburgh. Press
- Poetry and Other Works, 1940-2012; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains early and unpublished poems as well as materials related to published works, including notes, rough drafts, research material, original manuscripts, and page proofs. In this series are nineteen subseries; the first comprises early and/or unpublished poems while the remainder for each of Stern's published works. Within subseries 2-16, poems are arranged in the order in which they appear in the published work.
  New material was added to this series in 2015 and is organized alphabetically.
  - Early and Other Unpublished Poems, 1940-1992; 1.
    This subseries contains early and/or unpublished poems, mostly unfinished, and notes, which range in date from 1940 to 1992.
    - Early poems, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Early writings, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Old poems (unpublished) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Old poems (unpublished) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Notes, 1940-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bach (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jonah (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Soothing Position (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - In this my Clime (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Saturday Afternoon (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ishmael's Dream, circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Gropius, mid 1960s (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Anschluss, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Rejected poems (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Little Glass Cups (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Sweetest of all Blossoms (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - The Drunk (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Reegan (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Friendship (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Old Refrain (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Uncollected poems (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Uncollected poems (notes) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Unpublished drafts (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Black-eyed Susans (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - The Kiss (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Sumac (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Love Me (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Josephine's Garden (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Notes on mythology (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Notes on poetry of Judaism (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Notes, 1965-1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Notes, cira 1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Basara, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Hot Days, circa 1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Wrecker, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Beach poem, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Tree of God, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Essence of Paradise (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Wendell Wilkie (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Chicken Man, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Tomato Stakes, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Black Holes, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Noise poem, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Notes, circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Dead Bugs, circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Afternoon Nap, circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Notes and uncollected poems, circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Bird Death Throes, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Corn Forest, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - I am Fooled, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Boiling Alive, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Italy poem, circa 1980 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Map, circa 1980 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Poem about boxelder bug, early 1980s (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Enoch I (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Notes, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - That House, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Witch Haul / 3 Warm Days, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Swordfish, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Unpublished poems, circa 1992 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Unpublished poems, circa 1992 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Notes, circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - The Pineys, 1969; 2.
    In 1969 Stern's first major published work, The Pineys, was published in the Journal of the Rutgers University Library. The entire issue was dedicated to this lengthy poem about the people who reside in the Pine Barrens of New Jersey. It would later be included in Two Long Poems along with "Father Guzman," published in 1990.
    The subseries includes Stern's research, notes, various drafts (one of which completely handwritten in pencil), typescripts, and photographs.
    - Research notes (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Research articles (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Research publications (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Research newsclippings (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Notes (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Drafts (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Manuscript (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Typescripts and copies (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Drafts of Richard Hazley's introduction (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Proof pages from Journal of the Rutgers University Library (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Copy of The Pineys as it appeared in The Journal of the Rutgers University Library, XXXII, no. 2 (1969): 41-80 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Proposal for cover (newsclipping) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Rejoicings, 1973; 3.
    Rejoicings, published in 1973, was a collection of Stern's early poetry written between 1966 and 1972. Many of these poems were included in his first book of poetry, The Naming of Beasts, published by Cummington Press in 1972.
    Each folder contains notes and drafts for each of the poems, organized according to the order they appear in the book. The subseries also includes various typescripts, correspondence with publishers, reviews, and publicity.
    - Rejoicings (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - The Naming of Beasts (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - The Unity (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - His Animal is Finally a Kind of Ape (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Goons are Leaving (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bird Cursing (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - I will be a Romantic (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - On the Far Edge of Kilmer (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Going North on 202 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Poem of Life (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Weeds (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - When I Have Reached the Point of Suffocation (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Lost with Lieutenant Pike (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Immanuel Kant and the Hopi (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Pleistocene (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Heat Rises in Gusts (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Burst of Wind between Broadway and the River (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Top Rock (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Columbia the Gem (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Traitors (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Delaware West (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Planting Strawberries (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Dog in The House (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - In Carpenter's Woods (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Eroica (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - From the Pennsylvania Side (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Turning into a Pond (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Notebooks (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Rejection Letters (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Reviews (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Publicity and advertisements (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Biographical information (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence with Arthur Vogelsang of Metro Book Co. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Typescript for Metro Book Company (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Typescript (2 copies) for Cummington Press edition of Naming of Beasts (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Page Proofs from Cummington Press edition of Naming of Beasts (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Copyright Certificate for Naming of Beasts (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Rejoicings: Selected Poems / Gerald Stern. Fredericton, N.B.: Fiddlehead Poetry Books, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Lucky Life, 1977; 4.
    Stern's work became widely recognized after the 1977 publication of Lucky Life, which was that years Lamont Poetry Selection of the Academy of American Poets and was nominated for a National Book Award.
    The first part of the subseries includes drafts of individual poems and research notes, organized according the order they appear in the publication. These are then followed by materials that document the books publication and include proofs, reviews, and correspondence with various publishers.
    - Power of Maples (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Last Self-Portrait (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - At Bickford's (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - One Foot in the River (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Staus Park (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Let Me Please Look into my Window (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - I am so exhausted (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - On the Island (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - County Line Road (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Margie Moser's Garden (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - When it Gets Cold (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Days of Nietzsche (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Burying an Animal on the Way to New York (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Sensitive Knife (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - The One Thing in Life (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - On My Poor Road (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Blue Skies, White Breasts, Green Trees (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - The Sounds (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Sometimes When I Close my eyes (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Peace in the Near East (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Blue Tie (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Mentioning of the Souls (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Self-portrait (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Lobelia (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Three Tears (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Climbing This Hill Again (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Lucky Life (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Malgueña (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Pile of Feathers (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Feeding Prisoners (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Gold Flower (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Honey Locust (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Proverbs (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Bob Summers, and, Gert's Gifts (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Behaving like a Jew (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Love for the Dog (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Psalms (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - This is it (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - 96 Vandam (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - If You Forget The Germans (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - The Hungarian (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - God of Rain, God of Water (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Home from Greece (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Long Nose (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - If You Saw Me Walking (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - The Thaw (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Morning Harvest (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Peddler's Village (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Sweetness of Life (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Too Much, Too Much (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Underground Dancing (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Something New (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Notebook (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence from readers (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Reviews (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Publicity and advertising (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence with Godine Press (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence with Houghton Mifflin (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Typescript with handwritten corrections (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Bound uncorrected proof (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Galley proof (2 copies) (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Master proof (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence with Spring Church Book Company (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Correspondence with Carnegie-Mellon University Press (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Copyright releases (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Notes (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - The Red Coal, 1981; 5.
    The Red Coal, published in 1981, earned Stern the Melville Caine Award.
    The subseries consists of notes and drafts for individual poems, organized according to the order they appear in the book. The subseries also includes publication information, like correspondence with publishers and various proofs.
    - List of poems for possible inclusion (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Faces of Love (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Little White Sister (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Immensity (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Rotten Angel (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dangerous Cooks (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Good Friday, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Pick and Poke (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Royal Manor Road (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Modern Love (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - War against the Jews (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Little Did The Junco Know (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Lord, Forgive a Spirit (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Elaine Comparone (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Ice, Ice (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - One More Time the Lambs (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - The Sacred Spine (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - I Remember Galileo (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Potpourri (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Margritte Dancing (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - The Shirt Poem (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - June First (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Thinking about Shelley (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Cow Worship (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Joseph Pockets (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Phipps Conservatory (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Days of 1978 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - No Wind (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - June Fourth (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - The Angel Poem (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - St. Patrick's Day, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Visiting Florida Again (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Hanging Scroll (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - A Hundred Years from Now (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - The Poem of Liberation (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Acacia (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Your Animal (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - The Rose Warehouse (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - The Red Coal (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - There is Wind (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - The Way-We-Were Lounge (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Waving Goodbye (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - In the Shadows (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Dear Mole (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - My Hand (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - These Birds (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Arthur's Lily (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - The Picasso Poem (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - The Roar (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - For Night to Come (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Here I am Walking (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - List of Reviewers (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Reviews (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Publicity and advertisement (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Small press distributors (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence with Houghton Mifflin (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Typescript with handwritten corrections (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Galley proof (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Revised page proof (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Master proof (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Correspondence with Spring Church Book Co. (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Copyright releases (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Sales reports (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Father Guzman, 1982; 6.
    "Father Guzman," was Stern's first verse play originally published in The Paris Review in 1982 and later published in 1990 as Two Long Poems, which also included The Pineys.
    The subseries includes research materials, notes, drafts, proofs, correspondence, and a playscript.
    - Research materials (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Notes (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Drafts (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Stella Adler Studio of Acting (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Photocopy of play (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Paris Review galleys (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Proof pages from Paris Review (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Proof Pages for Two Long Poems (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Paradise Poems, 1984; 7.